<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tags on Another fairly useless page</title>
    <link>https://jsurmann.github.io/tags/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tags on Another fairly useless page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jsurmann.github.io/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reparing Shoes</title>
      <link>https://jsurmann.github.io/reparing-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsurmann.github.io/reparing-shoes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started working after graduation, my girlfriend told me that it was time to buy some decent shoes for everyday wear. Until then, I wore random trainers or low shoes, which did their job until they fell apart into various individual parts. Anyone who mentions the words &amp;ldquo;shoes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;duct tape&amp;rdquo; to my mom can expect some adventurous stories from my youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a random shoe store of a major chain, after a short search, we spotted what seemed to be the ideal pair of shoes. Reduced from 80 to 50 euros, brown leather with sneaker soles and comfortable. She liked it, so here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a year in which I wore the shoes regularly, but not daily, first disappointment spread. The sole of the shoes was completely worn in some areas, a plastic skeleton under the rubber came out piece by piece. This annoyed me for one reason in particular: the leather was still in good shape despite moderate care. Throwing it away was therefore out of the question initially. A local cobbler took care of the problem (&amp;ldquo;Holy shit&amp;rdquo;) and was finally able to glue new sneaker soles on my shoes for a total of 40 euros. With that, my shoes were initially fit again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, a few weeks after the repair, the inner lining of the shoes in the area of the heel dissolved piece by piece into the air. Simply sewing it back on at the existing seam was not possible, the inner lining would have had to be completely replaced. Although the leather was still in great condition, I gave up at that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months later, my little toes started drilling their way through the thin fabric of my running shoes. Throwing them away directly was out of the question, so I made two patches out of old clothes and sewed them to the shoes by hand over the holes. This really does not look great, but I still use the shoes today. Because again, all other parts of the shoes are perfectly fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the idea to put more on sustainability and repairability in shoes, I started to research. Because also my black leather shoes, which I wear on business trips, could use a little better care and maintenance. After all, I bought them long time ago for the senior prom. At a &lt;a href=&#34;https://schuhbedarf.de/&#34;&gt;dealer for shoemaking supplies in Dortmund&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to buy a starter set for shoe repairs. At the roadside I found an old metal toolbox, which I now use as a shoe repair box after a quick rust removal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of the tools I completely resoled my black leather shoes. In Amsterdam I later bought some red leather shoes second hand. These also got new soles. There is hope that my current shoes last much longer compared to the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/shoes10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shoe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Baking Meatloaf</title>
      <link>https://jsurmann.github.io/baking-meatloaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsurmann.github.io/baking-meatloaf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back, I had the loose idea to only eat meat products where I was involved in the production as much as possible within my capabilities. As a first step, I bought the necessary cuts from our local, self-slaughtering butcher. Making my own salami didn&amp;rsquo;t work in a first attempt (the mold took over), so I wanted to try something easier. On youtube I found a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pAdQl0RyILY&#34;&gt;good tutorial on how to make meatloaf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting up and mincing the pork shoulder, back fat, and pork cheek was an unusual experience. Chicken breast is quite a different thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meatloaf was fantastic, perhaps because the fat percentage was very high. I gave a few slices away to family, and froze the rest. The meatloaf also made a great bread topping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;m currently trying to eat vegan, there is no more meatloaf for now. But I can highly recommend to give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/meat9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meet Loaf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sewing</title>
      <link>https://jsurmann.github.io/sewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsurmann.github.io/sewing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My mother-in-law gave me an old sewing machine that she no longer needed. I was thrilled. An Elna Lotus ZZ from Switzerland, about 50 years old. The housing is made of metal. At home, however, it ended up in the closet for a while. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many attempts, I was able to thread the machine correctly and sew a first seam. The adventure begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;level-1&#34;&gt;Level 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know those colorful foam dishcloths you can buy in the supermarket? After a while they crumble all over the place and you have to buy new ones. So what could be more obvious than sewing rags for cleaning, washing up and personal hygiene? The material was old towels and shirts that had been sorted out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/sewing0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/sewing1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;level-2&#34;&gt;Level 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New boxer shorts were needed. With the help of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://magazin.snaply.de/boxershorts-naehen/&#34;&gt;free pattern&lt;/a&gt; I have now sewn together six copies. For the first I needed five hours, for the last two and a half. This means that the financial value per hour of work is higher than that of brewing beer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/sewing2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/sewing3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/sewing4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/sewing5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/sewing6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/sewing7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;level-3&#34;&gt;Level 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, my lightweight 40 liter backpack has been my travel companion. Because it is slim cut and has an opening only at the top, however, you always have to unpack a bunch of stuff, even to reach small items. Since buying new is out of question, we try to solve this problem with a zipper bought on the Internet for about 3 euros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/bag1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After carefully marking the center line, I separated the front of the backpack with scissors. Now there is no turning back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/bag2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To prevent the cut fabric from tearing, I first sew off the edges. With the boxer shorts this is trivial, but with the already sewn-together backpack it&amp;rsquo;s a challenge, especially at the bottom of the future zipper. Constantly the backpack gets stuck somewhere and hinders me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/bag3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before cutting the front, the two edges of the fabric touched. Now that a zipper with its width is sewn between the edges of the fabric, the two sides are a little too wide. Therefore, I sew both sides inwards. That also looks better. Theoretically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/bag4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sewing in the zipper, I need to sew the bottom end to the backpack. I do this by hand because the fabrics are too thick at this point and I can&amp;rsquo;t really sew with the machine at this position anyway. Well&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/bag5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if it is not visually perfect, the experiment worked and I do not have to buy another backpack after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/bag6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brewing Beer</title>
      <link>https://jsurmann.github.io/brewing-beer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsurmann.github.io/brewing-beer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why brew your own beer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t save money, for the price of the ingredients you can buy a finished beer in the supermarket. On top of that, it takes about 8 hours of work for 20 liters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It tastes very good, and it makes a great gift. But in the end, there is one reason above all to brew your own beer: Cause it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/beer0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beer brewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/beer1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beer brewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/beer2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beer brewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/beer3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beer brewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/beer4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beer brewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/beer5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beer brewing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing Rye</title>
      <link>https://jsurmann.github.io/growing-rye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jsurmann.github.io/growing-rye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since we have our own flour mill, I have been fascinated by grain. Small kernels that can be stored for a long time and become seed again when needed. In 2021 I decided to grow summer rye in our garden on 10 sqm. Nearly 3 kg of whole grain flour was the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/rye0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rye cultivation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/rye1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rye cultivation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/rye2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rye cultivation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/rye3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rye cultivation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/rye4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rye cultivation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/rye5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rye cultivation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the heads had dried indoors for a few weeks, I threshed the rye with the help of an electric drill. Then the grains were laboriously separated from the husks and straw residues. In this &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/FSEU77Qg4Nk&#34;&gt;youtube video&lt;/a&gt; I have documented these steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/rye6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rye cultivation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the good experience with the rye, I decided to plant sweet corn in 2022. The straw from the rye is reused as mulch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jsurmann.github.io/img/corn0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Corn cultivation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
